<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demos on Lorenzo Reitano</title>
    <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Demos on Lorenzo Reitano</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Health Protection Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 10:15:18 -0436</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>The Health Protection Dashboard is divided into five key sections, each focusing on specific outcomes and measures to improve public health. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore each section in detail:
Start Well: Key Outcome: Children are protected against key vaccine-preventable diseases by immunization. •	Coverage of the prenatal pertussis vaccine program (%): This section tracks the percentage of pregnant women who receive the pertussis vaccine, ensuring protection for both the mother and the unborn child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Clustering: Weather Stations</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 10:21:10 -0356</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description> Used a DBSCAN algorithm that that clusters Weather Stations by location and precipitation. Optimized the DBSCAN algorithm by using selecting for the most appropriate Epsilon and a Minimum Number of Samples to obtain the best clustering. Plotted a Folium Map of the Clustered Results. Link to GitHub Repository </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Classification: Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 10:21:10 -0356</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Used a Logistic Regression algorithm that predicts if clients will stay with the company (Log loss 60%), given Tenure, Age, Address, Income, Education, Employment and Equip. Pre-Processed the data by filtering for the most appropriate variables. Split the data with a Test Size of 0.2. Optimized the Logistic Regression algorithm by using an Liblinear Solver and a Inverse of regularization strength of 0.01 to obtain the best model. Plotted a Confusion Matrix of the Model Results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Classification: Cancer Cells Prediction</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 10:21:10 -0356</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Used a Support Vector Machines algorithm that predicts if patient&amp;rsquo;s cells are benign or malignant(F1-Score 97%) given Clump thickness, Uniformity of cell size, Uniformity of cell shape, Marginal adhesion, Single epithelial cell size, Bare nuclei, Bland chromatin, Normal nucleoli and Mitoses. Pre-Processed the data and dropped categorical values under Bare nuclei variable. Split the data with a Test Size of 0.2. Optimized the SVM algorithm by using an Polynomial Kernel to obtain the best model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Clustering: Customer Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:21:10 -0356</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description> Used a K-Means algorithm that clusters customers into groups based on Age, Education, Employment Years, Income and Debt. Pre-Processed the data deleting categorical variables. Normalized the data using the Standard Scaler. Optimized the K-Means number of Clusters to 3 and number of consecutive runs in terms of inertia to 12, in order to achieve the best model. 3-D Plotted the Model Results. Link to GitHub Repository </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain: Mining</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 10:15:18 -0436</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Created a BLOCK Class and a Mine algorithm. The BLOCKS are encrypted with the SHA256 hash function and each block has it&amp;rsquo;s difficulty increased by 1 starting from 4 zeros. Mining will loop through all the blocks guessing their Hash and will stop when the guessed hash starts with the number of zeros previously set by the Mining Function, after that it will attach the Block to the Blockchain. The function is programmed to fail if the Nonce reaches 1 × 10⁹ trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain: Mining</title>
      <link>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 10:15:18 -0436</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://relor91.github.io/Lorenzo_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Created a BLOCK Class and a Mine algorithm. The BLOCKS are encrypted with the SHA256 hash function and each block has it&amp;rsquo;s difficulty increased by 1 starting from 4 zeros. Mining will loop through all the blocks guessing their Hash and will stop when the guessed hash starts with the number of zeros previously set by the Mining Function, after that it will attach the Block to the Blockchain. The function is programmed to fail if the Nonce reaches 1 × 10⁹ trials.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
